Privacy Policy
==============

This Policy applies as between you, the User of this Website and Wide Angle Software Ltd, the owner and provider of this Website. This Policy applies to our use of any and all Data collected by us in relation to your use of the Website. Wide Angle Software is committed to ensuring that we are compliant with our obligations under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA). We are registered with the Information Commissioner's Office and our registration number is ZA517202.

* * *

### 1\. Definitions and Interpretation

In this Policy the following terms shall have the following meanings:

*   **"Data"** - means collectively all information that you submit to the Wide Angle Software via the Website. This definition shall, where applicable, incorporate the definitions provided in the European Economic Area (EEA) data protection law;
  
*   **“Cookie”** - means a small text file placed on your computer by this Website when you visit certain parts of the Website and/or when you use certain features of the Website. Details of the cookies used by this Website are set out in Clause 13;
  
*   **“Wide Angle Software”** - means Wide Angle Software of St. John's House Weston Road, Stafford, UK;
  
*   **“GDPR”** means the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679;
  
*   **“UK and EU Cookie Law”** - means the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 as amended by the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) (Amendment) Regulations 2011 & the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) (Amendment) Regulations 2018;
  
*   **“User”** - means any third party that accesses the Website and is not employed by Wide Angle Software and acting in the course of their employment;
  
*   **“Website”** - means the website that you are currently using (www.wideanglesoftware.com) and any sub-domains of this site (e.g. subdomain.wideanglesoftware.com) unless expressly excluded by their own terms and conditions;
  
*   **“Software”** - means the [products](https://www.wideanglesoftware.com/products/) available to download and purchase on this Website. All products available to download and purchase on this Website have been developed by Wide Angle Software staff; we do not offer downloads or offer technical support for third party software.

### 2\. Scope of this Policy

This Policy applies only to the actions of Wide Angle Software and Users with respect to this Website. It does not extend to any websites that can be accessed from this Website including, but not limited to, any links we may provide to social media websites.

### 3.1 Data Collected on our Website

3.1.1 IP address (automatically collected);

3.1.2 web browser type and version (automatically collected);

3.1.3 operating system (automatically collected);

3.1.4 a list of URLs starting with a referring site, your activity on this Website, and the site you exit to (automatically collected);

3.1.5 Personal data is only collected when a software purchase is made on our online store. The Personal Data that we may collect includes: Contact details, such as name, postal address, email address; We do NOT collect or store any financial Data; Purchases made on our store using PayPal as a payment method are also subject to the [PayPal Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full); Credit card purchases made on our store are processed by Stripe and are subject to the [Stripe Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/privacy).

### 3.2 Data Collected by our Software

3.2.1 The Software accesses your files and data locally on your computer. None of your files or data are transferred to Wide Angle Software or any third party.

3.2.2 For products that require activation to get full functionality, your activation details will be saved and verified by the software. Those products need to be connected to the internet for the sole purpose of verifying the validity of your purchased software license / activation code.

### 4\. Our Use of Data

4.1 We will retain your Personal Data for the purpose of identifying any purchases you made on our store and to enable us to provide your software activation details and customer support.

4.2 We will not share or disclose any of your personal information, other than for the purposes specified in this policy or where there is a legal requirement.

4.3 All personal Data is stored securely in accordance with the principles of the EEA data protection laws. For more details on security see Clause 12 below.

4.4 Any or all of the above Data may be required by us from time to time in order to provide you with the best possible service and experience when using our Website. Specifically, Data may be used by us for the following reasons:

*   4.4.1 To process your payment, communicate regarding a payment, and provide related customer service;
*   4.4.2 For audits, regulatory purposes, and compliance with industry standards;
*   4.4.3 To improve our products / services;
*   4.4.4 To send marketing communications.

### 5\. Third Party Websites and Services

Wide Angle Software does not share your information or data with third parties except in the following limited circumstances:

*   5.1 To facilitate you to make credit/debit card or PayPal payments, as set out in clause 3.5;
*   5.2 To facilitate activation code services provided by softWORKZ for the purposes of licensing your purchased software, please see the [softWORKZ privacy policy](https://www.softworkz.com/privacy.html);
*   5.3 To invite you to review our products or services. We use Trustpilot to collect your feedback which means that we will share your name, email address and reference number with Trustpilot for the Purpose. If you want to read more about how Trustpilot process your data, please see their [Privacy Policy](https://legal.trustpilot.com/for-reviewers/end-user-privacy-terms);
*   5.4 To conduct online surveys, questionnaires and research exclusively for the purpose of improving our products and services. We use SurveyMonkey to conduct online surveys, questionnaires and research, see the [SurveyMonkey’s privacy policy](https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/privacy/).

### 6\. Links to Other Websites

This Website may, from time to time, provide links to other websites. Wide Angle Software has no control over such websites and is in no way responsible for the content thereof. This Policy does not extend to your use of such websites. Users are advised to read the privacy policy or statement of other websites prior to using them.

### 7\. Changes of Business Ownership and Control

7.1 Wide Angle Software may, from time to time, expand or reduce our business and this may involve the sale and/or the transfer of control of all or part of Wide Angle Software. Data provided by Users will, where it is relevant to any part of our business so transferred, be transferred along with that part and the new owner or newly controlling party will, under the terms of this Policy, be permitted to use the Data for the purposes for which it was originally supplied to us.

7.2 In the event that any Data submitted by Users is to be transferred in such a manner, you will not be contacted in advance and informed of the changes.

### 8\. Controlling Use of Your Data

Wherever you are required to submit Data, you will be given options to restrict our use of that Data. This may include the following:

8.1. Unsubscribe

*   We may, from time to time, email you to invite you to review our products or services, or to make you aware of our other similar products and services which may be of interest to you. If you do not wish to receive emails from us for this purpose, or if you want to be removed from our electronic mailing list you can either select “unsubscribe” from any of the emails that we send or alternatively [contact us](https://support.wideanglesoftware.com/hc/en-us/requests/new).

8.2. Access and remove your Data as set out in Clause 11.

### 9\. Your Right to Withhold Information

9.1 You may access the Website without providing any Data at all. However, to use all features and functions available on the Website you may be required to submit certain Data.

9.2 You may restrict your internet browser’s use of Cookies. For more information see Clause 13.

### 10\. How long we keep your information for

We’ll hold your personal data, such as your name, email address and software activation codes on our systems for the longest of the following periods:

*   10.1 Up to 5 years on our activation code lookup service;
*   10.2 Any retention period that is required by law or regulation.

### 11\. Accessing your own Data

The General Data Protection Regulation gives individuals the right to access personal data that an organisation holds about them. The process for requesting this data is known as a "Subject Access Request". In particular, you have a right of access, rectification, restriction, opposition, erasure and data portability. Please [contact us](https://support.wideanglesoftware.com/hc/en-us/requests/new) if you wish to exercise these rights.

### 12\. Security

Data security is of great importance to Wide Angle Software and to protect your Data we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and administrative security measures designed to provide reasonable protection for your Personal Data against loss, misuse, unauthorised access, disclosure, and alteration. The security measures include firewalls, data encryption, physical access controls to our data centres, and information access authorisation controls.

### 13\. Cookies

13.1 This Website may place and access certain Cookies on your computer. Wide Angle Software uses Cookies to improve your experience of using the Website and to improve our range of products. Wide Angle Software has carefully chosen these Cookies and has taken steps to ensure that your privacy is protected and respected at all times.

13.2 All Cookies used by this Website are used in accordance with current UK and EU Cookie Law.

13.3 Before the Website places Cookies on your computer, subject to sub-Clause 13.4, you will be presented with Cookie permission popup window requesting your consent to set those Cookies. By giving your consent to the placing of Cookies you are enabling Wide Angle Software to provide the best possible experience and service to you. You may, if you wish, deny consent to the placing of Cookies; however certain features of the Website may not function fully or as intended.

13.4 The details of the cookies placed by wideanglesoftware.com are provided in our [Cookie Policy](https://www.wideanglesoftware.com/cookies/).

13.5 You can choose to enable or disable Cookies in your internet browser. By default, most internet browsers accept Cookies but this can be changed. For further details, please consult the help menu in your internet browser.

13.6 You can choose to delete Cookies at any time however you may lose any information that enables you to access the Website more quickly and efficiently including, but not limited to, personalisation settings.

13.7 It is recommended that you ensure that your internet browser is up-to-date and that you consult the help and guidance provided by the developer of your internet browser if you are unsure about adjusting your privacy settings.

### 14\. Changes to this Policy

Wide Angle Software reserves the right to change this Policy as we may deem necessary from time to time or as may be required by law. Any changes will be immediately posted on the Website and you are deemed to have accepted the terms of the Policy on your first use of the Website following the alterations.
